Noel Arteche

noel.arteche@gmail.com sites.google.com/view/noelarteche github.com/alephnoell

Summary

Born in 1998 in San Sebastián, Spain, where I studied Computer Science and Mathematics at the University of the Basque Country, with a year abroad at the KU Leuven in Belgium. I then graduated *cum laude* from the Master of Logic at the University of Amsterdam, while working as a researcher at the Logic and Reasoning (LoRea) group at the University of the Basque Country.

RESEARCH INTERESTS

- computational complexity theory
- theoretical computer science
- logic
- philosophy of mathematics
- philosophy of mathematical practice

EDUCATION

University of Amsterdam

MSc in Logic (120 ECTS)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

2020 - 2022

- Two-year master's program at the Institute for Logic, Language and Computation (ILLC).
 Courses in logic, theoretical computer science, mathematics and philosophy.
- Graduated cum laude.
- Thesis: Parameterized Compilability
 Supervisors: Ronald de Haan (ILLC, University of Amsterdam) and Hubie Chen (King's College London)

University of the Basque Country

San Sebastián, Spain

BSc in Computer Science (240 ECTS)

2016 - 2020

- Graduated first of my year, GPA: 9.43 (out of 10)
- Erasmus+ exchange at the KU Leuven (Belgium), during the academic year 2019-20.
 Completed 60 ECTS on master's level courses and wrote my thesis.
- Thesis: A Formal Language and Tool for QBF Family Definitions
 Supervisors: Marc Denecker (KU Leuven), Matthias van der Hallen (KU Leuven), Montserrat Hermo (University of the Basque Country).
 Results presented at the QBF Workshop of the SAT 2020 conference (see [2]).

Spanish National University of Distance Education (UNED)

Spain

BSc in Mathematics (incomplete)

2017 - 2019

- Studied half of the mathematics bachelor's degree part-time, while studying Computer Science; never fully completed it.
- GPA: 8.6 (out of 10)

SUMMER SCHOOLS

University of Göttingen

Göttingen, Germany

Hilbert-Bernays Summer School on Logic and Computation

October 2020

TEACHING

• Teaching Assistant at the University of Amsterdam

Spring 2022

Computational Complexity (6 ECTS · MSc course · 5314COCO6Y)

Lecturers: Ronald de Haan and Jan Maly

SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

Best Computer Science Student

Evert Willem Beth Scholarship
 Granted the E. W. Beth scholarship for my master's in logic at the University of Amsterdam
 Extraordinary BSc Degree Award
 Best Computer Science student at the University of the Basque Country
 Kutxa Fundazioa Award

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of the Basque Country

San Sebastián, Spain

Logic & Reasoning Group (LoRea), Faculty of Computer Science

- Predoctoral researcher

May 2021 – December 2021

- * Topic: The complexity of realizability for temporal logics
- * Supervisor: Montserrat Hermo
- Research internship June 2019 August 2019
 - * Topic: Empirical proof complexity of quantified Boolean formulas
 - * Supervisor: Montserrat Hermo

RESEARCH PAPERS

- [1] **N. Arteche** and M. Hermo, "Prime Implicant Enumeration via QBF Solvers", in QBF Workshop at the 24th International Conference on Theory and Applications of Satisfiability Testing, 2021.
- [2] **N. Arteche** and M. van der Hallen, "A Formal Language for QBF Family Definitions", in QBF Workshop at the 23rd International Conference on Theory and Applications of Satisfiability Testing, 2020.

Languages

- Spanish: native speaker
- **Basque:** native speaker, C1 certificate (EGA)
- English: fluent, C2 level (Cambridge Certificate of Proficiency in English)
- French: fluent, C2 level (DALF C2)
- Dutch: beginner, A1 level (diploma from the Instituut voor Levende Talen at the KU Leuven)

Extracurricular Activities

• Co-organiser of the Φ-Math reading group at the University of Amsterdam

2020 – 2021

Co-founded a reading group on the philosophy of mathematics at the Institute for Logic, Language and Computation.

• Cultural critique on video games

2016 – 2020

I was an editor at the Spanish online video game magazine Start, where I wrote about video games regarding narrative, language, medium essentialism and artificial intelligence. I was also an editor ZehnGames and I was invited to write a piece for the third issue of the Spanish video games essay compilation Deus Ex Machina. A complete list of my (academic and non-academic) texts is available on my personal site.